‪EIKYAKU NEWS
‪THE FUTURE
‪THE DAWN OF A NEW ERA
‪PUT SNACKS HERE
‪Dang! You're such an old man.
‪You with your newspaper,
‪your reading glasses…
‪I really don't think I'm that old.
‪Most people read the news
‪on their smartphones these days.
‪Go get yourself a smartphone. See?
‪WIFE - COMING HOME NOW
‪OKAY, LOVE YOU
‪LOVED THE LUNCH
‪YOU PACKED FOR ME
‪A smartphone, huh?
‪You're screwed going forward
‪if you don't have OINE.
‪They even use it for the news these days.
‪But this one still works.
‪Yum.
‪That's strange.
‪Why did the screen go black?
‪Huh?
‪KEEP THINGS TIDY AND IN ORDER
‪I'd better go and get this fixed.
‪You dolt. Ain't nobody around anymore
‪who can fix an old fossil like that.
‪Accept defeat
‪and go get yourself a smartphone.
‪God, that's good!
‪EIKYAKU NEWS
‪CHANGE YOUR LIFE
‪MESSAGE - CALENDAR - GALLERY
‪CAMERA - MEMO - SETTINGS
‪I went and got myself a smartphone,
‪but I have no idea how to use it.
‪GET THE LATEST NEWS
‪That's right.
‪Supposedly you can read the news on it.
‪Now, how to do it?
‪I guess I'll have a poke around.
‪PERSONAL DATA LEAK
‪VIA SMARTPHONE
‪IMPORTANT
‪10 MILLION YEN DUE NOW
‪VIRUS INFECTION - KO
‪It's no good. I can't do anything!
‪Huh?
‪PHOTO
‪What the…
‪What's with this screen?
‪How do I make it go back?
‪You want to know how to use a smartphone?
‪And hey, I didn't realize
‪you were the retro-flip-phone type.
‪Oh, yeah.
‪You do fit the bill.
‪Fit the bill?
‪Please teach me, Tayama.
‪Sure. I'll teach you.
‪You will? Thank you.
‪So? What do you need to know?
‪Well…
‪I'm embarrassed to say that
‪I don't even know the basic operations.
‪BLANK STARE
‪Tayama?
‪So start with the basics.
‪All right. Let's start with what
‪you're most likely to use.
‪If you will.
‪Basic number one.
‪I'm assuming you know how to get back
‪to the home screen, so we can skip that.
‪Sorry, could you show me how to do that?
‪Smartphones use the flick input method.
‪Give it a go. Hold the button, then flick
‪over to the character you want to type.
‪Flick?
‪All right.
‪"Ko." I want "ko…"
‪KI - KU - KE - KO
‪Flick?
‪KA
‪No!
‪That's not right.
‪Shall we set it
‪to a different input method?
‪Yes, please.
‪And I wanted to read the news
‪on my new smartphone…
‪Yeah, you can do that.
‪Really?
‪First, you have to open the App Store
‪to download a news app.
‪It's usually on the home screen.
‪And to use the App Store,
‪you're gonna have to create an account.
‪Once you've made your account, you log in…
‪USER'S MANUAL
‪…and download the news app.
‪Then you'll need to create
‪another account for that.
‪Here. I'll do it for you.
‪Thank you.
‪EIKYAKU NEWS
‪Wow, Tayama.
‪I feel like I can use this as a phone now.
‪Now all you have to do
‪is get used to it the more you use it.
‪And, Tayama,
‪there's one more thing
‪I'd like to ask of you.
‪Shoot.
‪Is there any way to make the text bigger?
‪What?
‪You're supposed to be useless
‪with smartphones.
‪How did you know
‪you can make the text bigger?
‪Well, because I did it on my flip phone.
‪Is it too hard to do?
‪Maybe it's complicated?
‪I mean, I'll do it for you, but…
‪But it's no excuse to give up on those.
‪All right.
‪I'll change the settings. Give it here.
‪And, Sasaki,
‪to celebrate your new smartphone debut…
‪how about I give you Yamada's number?
‪No. I don't need it. Thank you!
‪No. You can't, Tayama!
‪That's private information.
‪And besides,
‪it's Yamada's private information!
‪Welp. It's there now.
‪What?
‪How could you, Tayama?
‪Actually, I lied.
‪What?!
‪Okay. All done.
‪Tayama!
‪Here. That should be easier to read.
‪Thank you.
‪No! Not thank you!
‪Oh, no. Am so scared.
‪OPEN 24 HOURS - SUPER S
‪Hey, Yamada. See you out there.
‪See you.
‪Let's see what today's shift is.
‪REMEMBER TO KEEP
‪YOUR LOCKERS CLEAN
‪You didn't even notice
‪when I took your picture.
‪All right. Let's do this thing today.
‪HAPPY CORP.
‪Hey, Sasaki.
‪They say you can tell a man's personality
‪by the brand of smokes he chooses.
‪Who says?
‪They call it "brand readings."
‪The kids eat this shit up
‪at drinking parties these days.
‪Let's see what it says about me.
‪Apparently I'm the "devoted, loyal type"
‪who "never cheats!"
‪But it also says you're "oblivious"
‪and "can't read the room."
‪Hey! Those are minor details.
‪You can ignore those!
‪Why don't you read the room?
‪Did you hear me?
‪No?
‪-‪So this is a trendy topic?
‪-Which is it? Is that a smile?
‪Yeah. I've heard of those.
‪You have?
‪Only that they exist.
‪But aren't those things usually--
‪I learned of them through a coworker.
‪I thought it was so interesting.
‪HE MEANS WELL
‪All right. Let's see.
‪What does it say about you?
‪Well…
‪Here it is.
‪For me…
‪"Looks down on others,
‪despite masochistic tendencies."
‪What is that?
‪I can't… smoke my cigarette…
‪Seriously?
‪What about you?
‪"Has a dual personality
‪and an exceptionally strong libido."
‪These things always
‪end on something dirty.
‪The person who wrote these
‪must have some harsh biases.
‪Though they got me right,
‪which gave me a laugh.
‪INSIDE - OUTSIDE
‪Please forgive me.
‪Why are you on your knees?
‪Where's your cigarette? And your glasses?
‪I didn't realize these readings
‪would take such a strange turn.
‪I'm terribly sorry
‪for putting you through it.
‪I'm sorry for making you say that.
‪Well, I certainly do hate dirty jokes.
‪HATES DIRTY JOKES
‪But you only brought it up
‪because you thought it was trendy, right?
‪You meant well,
‪and now you're apologizing for it?
‪Silly Sasaki.
‪I'm not mad.
‪Let's get back to smoking.
‪Tayama.
‪I think it was right about you
‪having a dual personality.
‪It's been on my mind, but I haven't
‪been able to put it into words.
‪But I get it now.
‪You play it cool,
‪but you're really a big softie.
‪That's who you really are. Right?
‪Tayama?
‪That's the one
‪you were about to smoke, right?
‪Thanks.
‪Do forgive me. How could I forget?
‪Want me to give you a light?
‪Tayama… are you mad?
‪I'm not mad. See? I'm smiling.
‪I really am sorry.
‪What for?
‪OPEN 24 HOURS - SUPER S
‪TASTY RICE CRACKERS
‪After all is said and done,
‪I really did offend her yesterday.
‪Thank you, and have a nice day.
‪Do I even have the right
‪to line up at Yamada's register?
‪No.
‪Next!
‪This register is open.
‪Yes.
‪Trouble in paradise?
‪Wish I could've seen it.
‪Sorry to bring you all the way
‪out here in this heat today.
‪No, it's fine.
‪Please. Have some tea.
‪Thank you.
‪You're welcome.
‪Those files you sent over?
‪You sure saved us some heartache.
‪Even the president was thrilled.
‪"Gotta hand it to Happy Corp., " he said!
‪I'm glad to hear it.
‪Hello, everyone.
‪It's been as hot as summer
‪since the end of Golden Week, hasn't it?
‪We've all started wearing
‪the Cool Biz style.
‪That's wonderful.
‪Happy Corp. doesn't allow it
‪until it's officially summer though.
‪That's rough, man.
‪TOMORROW'S WEATHER
‪Northern Japan will see…
‪All right then.
‪I look forward to seeing you again.
‪Yes. Me too.
‪Where are you off to now? Back to work?
‪No. I should be able
‪to go straight home today.
‪How lovely.
‪I know you're always working so hard.
‪I hate how it stays hot into the evenings.
‪What am I going to do
‪when summer really rolls around?
‪You like your ice cream?
‪Yeah!
‪-You've been sweating so much.
‪-It's hot.
‪Maybe I'll get
‪an ice cream for the road too?
‪Wait!
‪It really does get packed in the evenings.
‪Hey, wait!
‪Yamada?
‪She's on the evening shift today?
‪What a great day
‪this is turning out to be.
‪Thank you, and have a nice day.
‪Short sleeves?
‪Thank you for the point card.
‪Wow!
‪Today's the seasonal change in uniform?
‪Why does this feel so refreshing?
‪And Yamada looks…
‪cute--
‪I don't need an ice cream after all.
‪I'm going home.
‪ICE CREAM BAR
‪Yamada was there yesterday,
‪but you didn't buy anything from her.
‪Why not?
‪You saw me from somewhere again?
‪A large, middle-aged man loitering by
‪the entrance sticks out like a sore thumb.
‪Sorry to be a bother.
‪So? Why no purchase?
‪It was hot yesterday,
‪so I wanted an ice cream.
‪Okay?
‪But the store was full of negative ions,
‪which cooled me down quick.
‪Negative ions?
‪Well, well.
‪And here I was thinking it was Yamada's
‪short sleeves that blew the heat away.
‪Bingo.
‪No. No. No!
‪I'm just thankful to all retail workers
‪who wear appropriate seasonal wear,
‪and that includes Yamada.
‪So you don't think she's cute.
‪I never said…
‪I think she's the type of person
‪who looks good in short sleeves.
‪That's quite a sweat
‪you're working up there.
‪Well, it's hot today…
‪Aren't you hot in that jacket?
‪I've got light layers on underneath.
‪I've got nothing on you.
‪Really?
‪Yeah.
‪See?
‪Tayama! I'm sorry…
‪I'm sorry for looking at your stomach!
‪Doesn't…
‪Doesn't your midriff get cold?
‪No? No? No?
‪YAMADA'S SHORT SLEEVES
‪Beautiful!
‪TAYAMA'S MIDRIFF
‪Yay!
‪Aren't you cold? Are you all right?
‪Dang, this old geezer…
‪Tayama.
‪If you'd like…
‪There's still a cold breeze out at night.
‪You don't have to wear it
‪if you don't want to--
‪What? Tayama. I'm sorry.
‪I thought you might want
‪to layer it over your stomach.
‪I wasn't telling you to cover up!
‪Did I offend…
‪you?
‪Tayama?
‪Shut it, arms man.
‪Arms man?
‪I don't get it.
‪Arms man? What's that?
‪I guess I really am dense
‪when it comes to these things.
‪So you like arms
‪more than you do midriffs, Sasaki.
‪SQUISH
‪LEMON CHUHAI
‪Guess I'm laying off
‪the ramen for a while.
‪Subtitle translation by: Rychelle Brittain